<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ecosystem on Random Thoughts</title>
    <link>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/tags/ecosystem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ecosystem on Random Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 18:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/tags/ecosystem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Should Early-Stage startups invest in Business Development?</title>
      <link>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2022/01/10/should-startups-invest-in-bd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2022/01/10/should-startups-invest-in-bd/</guid>
      <description>As a practitioner, I get this question from the newly minted CEOs a lot of time. They understand the math behind their company’s primary Go-To-Market (GTM) motion. And also might have built a working model on how to scale if the product-market fit emerges. Most of the time, it goes something like this - For a top-down enterprise selling motion - “If I hire X Sales/SE/Ops guys, they can get me to Y revenue, if there is more demand, I will just replicate and use a bigger multiplier”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iAd - Did Google hold a red cloth to the charging bull?</title>
      <link>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2010/04/09/apple-ad-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2010 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2010/04/09/apple-ad-google/</guid>
      <description>With iAd now officially announced and details starting to trickle in, the fight is officially on. Google and Apple are now in direct competition, and this time it is on Google’s home turf. Forbes has a good take on what is missing in the iAd efforts.
The four keys ones are -
 Creative agencies build ads in Flash. There is no comparable tool for creating HTML5 creatives. As a media agency (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Business Model getting clearer - The 3 options</title>
      <link>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2009/05/29/apple-bizmodel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2009 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2009/05/29/apple-bizmodel/</guid>
      <description>Google is finally giving more clarity on the business models for device vendors and service providers. The NY Times article mention three options -
  The obligation-free option: Free Android, load onto their devices, and provide access to as many or as few apps as they want. No preload popular Google applications, like Gmail or Google calendar.
  The small strings attached option: Same as Option 1, except that manufacturers sign a distribution agreement to include on the phone Google applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple&#39;s Secret Weapon </title>
      <link>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2007/07/07apple-secret-weapon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2007 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2007/07/07apple-secret-weapon/</guid>
      <description>More than a week has passed since the “iPhone” release, and hopefully, we can start looking beyond Jesus Phone. It seems like things are getting back to normal, and Apple is also ready to focus back on iPod. It is a good time to talk about things beyond iPhone. One of the key capabilities that Apple had been quietly rolling out into its products and is very rarely talked about is the networking platform - &amp;ldquo;Bonjour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digitization of Desktop </title>
      <link>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2007/04/14/digitization-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2007 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2007/04/14/digitization-desktop/</guid>
      <description>Virtualization driven desktop consolidations are very much in the news now. VMware with VDI got it started, but others are rallying and catching on to the bandwagon very quickly. Though late to the party,Citrix, Microsoft and others are not sitting idle and are quickly catching up. Recent news on the licensing changes from Microsoft to support Vista Enterprise Centralized Desktops (VECD) looks like the tipping point for the adoption of desktop virtualization by the mainstream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How IBM leverages Open Source</title>
      <link>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2006/11/28/ibm-opensource/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2006 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2006/11/28/ibm-opensource/</guid>
      <description>Dana Blankenhorn recently blogged about IBMs reaction to Sun’s Java plan and their approach to the open source ecosystem. I think Dana summarizes it very well. IBM believes Open Source is a great technology floor on which others and even IBM builds. But as Dana points out, it is naive to treat IBM as a Solutions and Services company with the rest of the software industry players, primarily software vendors like Oracle, SAP, RedHat, and Microsoft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PCs and web2.0 : Part 2 PCs the perfect Interaction Engines</title>
      <link>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2006/11/05/personal-computer-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2006 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2006/11/05/personal-computer-part2/</guid>
      <description>Last week I talked about how the evolving push towards services-based applications threatens the existing PCs role. There is a widespread fear that web2.0 and SaaS will finally kill the thick Moore&amp;rsquo;s law-driven PC, and we all will be either working on dumb terminals or the cell phone size devices that will run all our applications. Skeptics and realists are arriving and last week&amp;rsquo;s blog byJohn Milan talked about how Google&amp;rsquo;s desktop based application strategy is evolving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PCs and web2.0 : Part 1 What made PCs so successful</title>
      <link>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2006/10/19/personal-computers-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2006 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2006/10/19/personal-computers-part1/</guid>
      <description>There is enough written about the PCs&#39; success and the overall impact it has had over decades. PCs are attributed to increased productivity, economic gains, and the creation of the Information Technology business. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to delve into it very much. I am looking at PCs and their role in the changing landscape of services-based applications, call it web2.0, SOA, or some flavor of SaaS. I am using the term PCs very loosely to refer PC</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intel: Meet Darwin</title>
      <link>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2006/06/26/intel-meet-darwin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2006 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2006/06/26/intel-meet-darwin/</guid>
      <description>Pretty well put by Geoff Moore. Excellent guidance and lesson for anybody trying to be a platform player.
 Dealing with Darwin demands counter-intuitive actions, specifically when the environment has changed in some fundamental way that invalidates one’s traditional source of competitive advantage. … The competitive advantage position is changed. It remains to be seen if Intel can adapt and define competitive advantages in adjacencies.
This past week Intel surprised analysts with the latest in a set of uncharacteristically weak performances, especially in comparison with AMD.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
