<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leadership on Random Thoughts</title>
    <link>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/tags/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Leadership on Random Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rushing to Cloud Marketplaces is not a strategy</title>
      <link>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2019/12/25/rushing-to-cloud-marketplaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2019/12/25/rushing-to-cloud-marketplaces/</guid>
      <description>For software vendors it is not just about getting on the catalog but also about building a product that maximizes the massive channel these cloud marketplaces open up
Cloud Marketplaces from mega cloud platforms like Microsoft Azure, Amazon AWS and Google GCP are in now, AWS Marketplace alone has 7500+ listing and over a million subscribers. Cloud is fundamentally transforming the supply chain of software and services. For any independent software vendor (ISV) today it is hard to ignore the havoc these cloud platforms are causing to their established way of building, marketing and selling software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Business Model getting clearer - The 3 options</title>
      <link>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2009/05/29/apple-bizmodel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2009 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2009/05/29/apple-bizmodel/</guid>
      <description>Google is finally giving more clarity on the business models for device vendors and the service providers. The NY Times article mention three options -
  The obligation-free option: Fre Android, load onto their devices and provide access to as many or as few apps as they want. No preload popular Google applications, like Gmail or Google calendar.
  The small strings option: Same as Option 1, except that manufacturers sign a distribution agreement to include on the phone Google applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple: The Great Leadeship - &#39;The change from within&#39;</title>
      <link>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2008/05/27/apple-leadership-within/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2008 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jobigeorge.netlify.app/2008/05/27/apple-leadership-within/</guid>
      <description>Today there is a great post by Geofferey Helt at Minnyvale on how Steve transformed Apple..In summary..
The fundamental challenge facing the leadership team at Apple is not about strategy, but rather capacity. The question that stands in the way of its heroic future is: How do we redesign the organization of our business to deliver on the following interconnected fronts?
 Doubling the number of Apple stores to facilitate broader adoption.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
